前
我流血啦…我死啦
Blood. Blood. Blood. And death.
情
提
要
好啦，你也演太大了
All right. You know what? You're milking it.
蹄
可以收工了
Besides, I think we got it.
可以收工啦，谢咯，长舌妇
We got it up there. Thank you, Yakkity-yak.
你整个突破盲肠了
You laid it all out beautifully.
我嫁祸给狮明德，也能嫁祸给你
I framed Lionheart. I can frame you too.
尽管说你的片面之词吧
It's my word against yours.
事实上…
Actually...
我会利用动物方城市所有猎食者
And I'll dart every predator in Zootopia
来保持现状
to keep it that way.
是你的片面之词
- It's your word against yours. - Huh?
这叫说话的艺术，宝贝
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
砰
Boom.
不寻常的拍档…
Unlikely duo
最新进展
出人意料的搭档揭露惊天阴谋
出人意料的搭档揭示惊天阴谋
动物城电视网
（动物方城市新闻台）
哈茱蒂，本市第一位兔警员
Judy Hopps, the city's first bunny cop,
跟胡尼克，一位平凡的狐狸
and Nicholas Wilde, a small-time street fox,
前市长杨咩咩入狱
一起揭穿了杨咩咩市长的阴谋
uncovered a conspiracy by Mayor Bellwether today
用胡萝卜玩具录音笔
using a toy carrot recorder pen.
我也能嫁祸给你
I can frame you too.
后来，胡尼克加入ZPD警局
Wilde later joined the ZPD himself,
成为动物方城市史上
where the pair are now the very first bunny-fox team
动物方城市警察学校
第一组兔狐搭档
in the history of Zootopia.
新任市长暨前演员马立夯
New mayor and former actor Brian Winddancer
在动物方城市气候墙
hailed the two
发明一百周年庆祝活动上
during celebrations for the 100th anniversary
表扬他们两位
of the invention of Zootopia's weather walls
气候墙让各种环境和动物
that allowed all environments and all animals
鱼镇市场
克拉克·比目鱼
脂肪大厨
凉快一下
能在一个城市中共存
to coexist in one city.
这是我们建城百年纪念
This is our Zootennial!
如果出身卑微的乡下兔子
And if a lowly country bunny
跟可能有案底的奸诈狐狸
and a shifty, likely criminal fox
能不顾他们惊人的差异
can ignore their vast, vast differences
彻底化解偏见和刻板印象
and solve bias and stereotype forever,
那也许我们都能接受彼此的差异
then maybe we can all embrace our differences
一起成为更好的动物
and be better zoogether.
我们会侦破新案子，让世界更美好
We're gonna crack a new case, make the world a better place,
成为史上最棒的搭档
and be the greatest partners of all time.
我们又没那么不同
I mean, we're not that different.
在ZPD，搭档合作是成功的基石
At the ZPD, partnership is the cornerstone of success.
想把坏人绳之以法
You want to put bad guys away?
就要有默契，每天合作无间
Be on the same page. Every day.
今天的坏蛋是这个海关检查员
Now today's bad guy is this customs inspector
这个家伙一直在利用船坞
who's been smuggling illegal overseas cargo
走私非法的海外货物
through the city's shipyard.
行动由霍队长和阿杜队长带领
Captains Hoggbottom and Truffler will lead.
何大马、胖胖，左翼
Higgins, Bloats, flank left.
老却、宝龙，右翼
Chèvre, Bûcheron, right.
-留守中间的是斑宝兄弟 -斑宝
-And down the middle, the Zebros. -Zebros!
哈胡组，我知道你们急着求表现
Hopps and Wilde, I know you're eager to prove yourselves,
但身为菜鸟，你们只能观摩
but as rookies, you will observe only
让资深团队教你们如何…
and watch the veteran teams show you how it's...
（哈，胡）
局长，嗨
Chief, hi.
要找尼克和茱蒂的话
If you're looking for Nick and Judy,
他们说：「没问题」
they said they got it.
他们已抵达现场，还带着他们的宝宝
And they are already on site, with their baby!
（船坞）
这方法可行吗？
Are you sure this'll work?
是你说我们得采取突袭
You're the one that said we needed a bust.
跟着我做好吗？自然一点
Just follow my lead, okay? Act casual.
嘿 -来了
- Hey! - Here we go.
哈啰
Hello?
这里是管制区
This whole area's restricted.
你们不能来
You can't be here.
狐狸和兔子，好吧
Whoa. Fox and bunny. Okay.
没错，更是骄傲的父母
Yes, but proud parents first.
你是… -检查员
- Mister... - Inspector.
史奴利检查员
Inspector Snootley.
检查员？你们都做什么啊？
Inspector? What do you do?
防止非法物品透过这些货柜走私进来？
Ensure that nothing illegal gets smuggled here in one of these cargo containers?
这种问法怪怪的
That's a weird way to ask that.
反正你们得离开，不能进来
Anyway, you gotta leave. You can't be here.
等等，等等
- Oh. - Wait. Wait.
他说得对，真是的
He's right, gosh darn it.
你说得对，先生
You are right, sir.
我们该想清楚的，对吧，宝贝？
I guess we should've thought this through. Right, babe?
在我们决定来这里
Before we decided to come down here
到这座美丽的工业船坞
to this beautiful industrial shipyard
庆祝宝贝儿子生日之前就该想到的
to celebrate the big day of our birthday boy.
今天他生日？
It's his birthday?
对，这是第一次…
Yeah. First one since...
在那场意外之后
...since the accident.
这个小臭蛋最大的愿望
And, you know, the one thing this little stinker wished for...
除了有一天能把尾巴接回去
...aside from one day getting his tail reattached,
就是能看到火车
was to see a choo-choo.
说不定还能请列车长在他的石膏上签名
And to maybe get a toot-toot conductor to sign his cast.
不过我敢打赌
But I'm betting a customs inspector
让海关检查员签名一定更棒
would be even better.
真的吗？
Really?
好吧，为了孩子，为了孩子
All right. For the kid. For the kid.
你真是大好人
Oh, you're a saint.
非常谢谢你，签哪条腿都行
We thank you so much. Here you go. Either leg.
两腿都签也好，无所谓
Or both. I don't care.
加上一点涂鸦吧
Maybe put a doodle on it.
不用很完美
Doesn't need to be perfect.
他的眼睛看不见
He's also legally blind.
我画了小火车，因为你喜欢火车
I put a little train there because I know you like trains.
快啊…
Come on. Come on. Come on.
摇一摇 -我知道
- Just jiggle it. - Yes. I know.
快 -我会啦
- Hurry! - I got this.
摇一下…
Jiggle it. Jiggle it. Jiggle it!
哈胡组，你们没得到授权
Hopps and Wilde, you are not authorized.
退下，等候支援
Stand down and wait for backup.
嘟嘟
Toot, toot.
是条子 -别跑
- It's the fuzz! - Stop!
站住，警察！ -大家快跑
- Stop in the name of the law! - Everybody run!
好吧，认栽了
Well, can't win 'em all.
别挡路，傻兔子
Get outta the road, you dumb bunny.
我可不这么认为
Hmm. Agree to disagree.
我的猪猪改装车，太离谱了
My hog rod! This is a snoutrage!
哈胡双雄追捕嫌犯
Hopps and Wilde in pursuit of suspect
开着偷来的外烩餐车，往东…
in a stolen catering van heading east...
别闹了
Stop it.
穿过绵羊村往东逃逸
...heading east through Sheepshire.
（庆祝建城百年）
真漂亮
Beautiful.
我要剃成那样
I'll have what he's having.
宝贝，坐你开的车害我毛都吓白了
Darling, I believe your driving is giving me some white hairs.
还有，我永远都要坐副驾吗？
Also, am I always gonna be in the passenger's seat?
要是以后都这样…
'Cause if we're establishing sides...
（警察）
退下，菜鸟
Back off, rookies!
交给正牌军处理
Let the real teams handle it.
队长，我们是正牌军 -捷径，走隧道
- Ma'am, we are a real team. - Shortcut. Take the tunnel.
（鼹荷兰隧道）
退下，菜鸟
Stand down, noobs.
交给我们
We got him.
铺刺钉 -铺刺钉
- Rolling spikes! - Rolling spikes!
我恨那只傻兔子
I hate that dumb bunny.
（建城百年游行）
（阿慕斯波许外烩）
（牛泽西游行）
（豚化亚氮）
我要跳了 -什么？
- I'm gonna jump. - What?
不，你…
No, no. What are you...
萝卜头，我们开个小组会议
Carrots, hey... I would like to call a partner meeting.
不，萝卜头
No, Carrots!
茱蒂！
- Judy!
请大家和我一起默哀
Please join me in a moment of silence
向敬爱的气候墙发明者厉班瑟致敬
for our beloved weather wall inventor Ebenezer Lynxley.
斑宝！
Zebros!
爬虫类？
Reptile?
（蛮牛局长）
局长，那两个在门外
Chief, those two are out of control!
动物方城市不只是个哺乳类城市
Zootopia ain't just a mammal city.
还有一个小型隐密的爬虫类族群
It has a secret, tiny reptile population,
但大部分住在海外
though most live abroad.
当然，动物方城市容不下蛇
Of course, Zootopia does not allow snakes.
这里起码一百年没见过一条蛇
There ain't been one of those around here for at least a hundred years.
鳞甲怪谭
"Scales and tales of the weird."
（聂狸宝的鳞甲怪谭，只有真相）
对，我不确定聂狸宝
Yeah, not sure Nibbles Maplestick
是不是最可靠的来源
is our most reliable source.
兔子、黄毛狗，给我进来
Bunny, orange dog, in here now.
局长，今天结果不理想，但食蚁兽被捕了
Sir, today may not have been ideal, but the anteater was captured.
是斑宝抓的
By the Zebros!
-斑宝 -闭嘴
- Zebros! - Shut it!
斑宝
Zebros.
是我们
It was us.
但更重要的是
But more importantly,
我相信我们可能有了重大发现
I believe we may have made a significant discovery.
赃车里有海外走私进来的条板箱
The stolen van contained a smuggled crate from overseas,
建城百年的折页传单
pamphlets for the Zootennial,
和某种爬虫类的皮
and some type of reptile skin.
我已经送样本去检验
I've already sent samples for testing.
如果你… -需要检验的是你们
- And if you... - What needs testing is you!
你们俩拆掉了半座城市
You two tore up half the city.
因为你们，我们得找来重磅组
Because of you, we had to call in Jumbo Unit
把一只犬羚从低音号里弄出来
to remove a dik-dik from a tuba!
-快出来了，你会… -拜托，不要
-You're almost out. You're gonna be... -No! Please, no!
谁去接住他？
Who's catching him?
抱歉，视频能重播吗？我没戴眼镜
Sorry, could you show me that clip again? Wasn't wearing my glasses.
你们有没有违抗
Did you or did you not
我叫你们退下的命令？
disobey a direct order to stand down?
局长，当时在进行追捕
Sir, we were in pursuit.
根据第六条B款规定
And article 6, paragraph B states,
「若带队警员认为…」
"If the lead officers think that..."
你们不是带队警员
You are not lead officers!
上次是你们走运
You're one-hit wonders
你们该回去开违规罚单，卖冰棍才对
who should go back to meter maiding and slinging pawpsicles!
让我来，我想有人嫉妒我们能开猪猪车
If I may, I think someone's just jealous that we got to drive the squeal mobile.
还是，你以为那是你妈妈？
Or maybe you thought it was your momma.
够了！大家都出去
- Enough! Everybody out.
哈警员
Officer Hopps,
再不情愿我还是得承认，我欣赏你
despite my best efforts to avoid it, I like you.
但是，像这样的夸张行径
But this need to overdo it
让你们两个成了今天的头条
made both of you a headline today.
让我和警局脸上无光
And it reflects badly on me, on the department,
老实说
and frankly
也让其他追随你脚步的兔子难看
on any bunny hoping to follow in your footsteps.
不是每个案子都能拯救世界
Not every case is going to save the world.
叩叩
Knock-knock.
嗨
Hi.
这听起来像是你们私下的悄悄话
You know, this kinda... this sounds a lot like a... just a "you guys" conversation.
我还是识相点离开…
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna go ahead and...
为何你做什么都这么吊儿郎当？
Is there a reason why you don't take anything seriously?
有童年创伤就爱把玩笑当防卫机制
Jokes are a classic defense mechanism ,for someone with a traumatic childhood.
成年后还想受创伤吗？
Would you like a traumatic adulthood?
不想
I would not.
我允许你们合作是因为
I allowed you to work together
你们曾对本市有重大贡献
because you did this city a great service.
（哈胡侦破哺乳类失踪案）
But today, you messed it all up.
但是今天，你们全搞砸了
现在
And now, some are questioning
有声音质疑你们是否该成为搭档
whether you should've been partners in the first place.
局长… -所以
- Sir... - So,
别再追捕想象出来的爬虫类
instead of chasing imaginary reptiles,
我要把你们调离外勤…
I am pulling you from the field...
-什么？ -交付一项
-What? -...and giving you a new assignment
保留给你们这种特殊组合的新任务
reserved for special teams like yourselves.
要是失败
Fail at this,
我就不得不拆散你们
and I will have no choice but to split you up.
以后就没有哈胡组了
There will be no more Hopps and Wilde.
但你们若有自己以为的那么厉害
But if you're as good as you think you are,
这就是你们发光的时刻
this is your moment to shine.
欢迎来到「危机搭档课程」
Welcome to Partners in Crisis,
专为相处困难的搭档办的工作坊
a workshop for duos heading for disaster.
我是你们的咨询师茸茸博士
I'm your therapy animal, Dr. Fuzzby.
你们会来
And you are here
是因为彼此不合的搭档往往需要…
because mismatched pairings often need a little more work
多一点的磨合
to make them work.
葛雷格，我们已经谈过了
Greg, we talked about that.
这样会让马隆怎样？
What are we making Marlon?
很不舒服，没错
Uncomfortable. Yes.
法兰欣，克拉克虽然是老鼠
And, Francine, Clark may be a mouse,
但他仍然是你的搭档
but he is your partner first.
（你好，我叫克拉克）
今天有两位新的「不搭档」
And we have two new "apart-ners."
跟我们聊聊你们崩坏人生的转折点
Can you tell us about your journey to dysfunction junction?
这个嘛，我们成为正式搭档一周了
Well, we've been official partners for one week.
一周纪念快乐
Happy anniversary.
其实…我们的关系没有崩坏
And we're not dysfunctional at all, actually.
配合良好，比好再更好
Functioning fine. Better than fine.
我们还拯救了全市
And we did sort of save the city,
所以来这里好像是天大的误会
so us being here kinda seems like a huge misunderstanding.
注意她抢着回答，没让搭档插话
Notice how she answered first, did not allow her partner to speak,
似乎不肯面对事实
seems to be in a state of denial
还不断抖脚，压抑不适感
and taps her foot when she's suppressing discomfort.
观察到她的不适情绪
And observe the source of her discomfort
来自她缺乏安全感的搭档
represented by the disconnected affectation
所表现出的疏离
of her emotionally insecure partner.
但只要努力，他们第二年就能配合良好
But with hard work, they'll be on the same page by year two.
现在，我们先向搭档问好
But for now, let's begin by greeting our teammate.
谁想先开始？
Who would like to go first?
谢谢你，乔
Thank you, Joel.
好，可惜凯伦选择把乔的笑容
Okay, unfortunately, Karen has chosen to see Joel's smile
当成攻击的表现
as a sign of aggression.
冷静，凯伦，凯伦，冷静
Hackles down, Karen. Karen, hackles down.
乔，安全暗号是「椰子」
Joel, the safe word is "coconut."
椰子
Coconut!
（椰子冷饮）
好，我们再跟局长开一次会
Okay, we have to set another meeting with the Chief.
保证我们会改进
Promise we'll be better.
斑宝
Zebros!
你少开口，最好都不要
You talk back less. Maybe not at all.
或是照我的办法
Yeah. Or we go with my playbook,
我们就保持低调
and we just lay low.
困在办公室就不能证明我们的本事
We cannot prove ourselves if we are stuck in that room.
跟牛老大抱怨，他会要我们待更久
And if we complain to Chief Beef, he'll just make us stay longer.
聪明点，别强出头
Play it smart. Stay off the radar.
别因此泄气，好吗？
And don't let it get to you. Okay?
因为我们是梦幻团队
'Cause we are the dream team.
抱歉，保罗
Sorry, Paul.
（资讯科技）
快铺红地毯，超级警察来了
Roll out the red carpet. Here's the super cops.
狐狸都怎么说的？
- Hey, what does the fox say?
烂透了
You suck!
别激动，搭档
Easy, partner.
问你一件事
Let me ask you something.
我们是好搭档吗？
Do you think we're a good team?
当然
Of course.
只是…
I just...
我只想知道怎样才能向其他人证明
I just wish I knew what we had to do to prove it to everyone else.
或许我们不用向谁证明任何事
Or maybe we don't have to prove anything to anybody.
必须，一定要
- We do. Forever. - Oof!
大家越早明白…
And the sooner everyone sees
（第一次搭档就上手）
狐兔能当好搭档越好，慢慢看
a fox and a bunny can be great partners, the better. Enjoy it.
-我买了两本 -我宁愿咬断我的手臂
-I got two. -I'd rather chew off my own arm.
一周纪念快乐
Happy anniversary!
椰子
Coconut!
（大象健身房）
（哈茱蒂与胡尼克：新搭档破大案）
在电视上看到你了，都还好吗？
So, saw you on TV. You okay?
一切都很好，妈
Everything's fine, Mom.
大家都知道「很好」是求救讯号
Uh-oh. Everyone knows "fine" is a cry for help.
还有谁在求救呢？
You know who else cried for help?
卡在低音号里的那只犬羚
That dik-dik stuck in that tuba.
老讲那只犬羚，你跟狐狸搭档都聊什么？
Oh, him and the dik-dik. What does your fox partner say?
尼克的话不多
Well, Nick's not really a talker.
你们的确非常不同
Well, you two are very different.
农场长大的小镇英雄
Small-town hero raised on a farm.
街头长大的大城市骗子
Big-city crook raised on the streets.
我天天都期盼你快回老家生宝宝
I pray every day that you'll come back home and make babies.
妈
Mom!
记住搭档的第一原则
Just remember the first rule of partnerships.
-计较对错，不如开心就好 -真的
-You can be right or you can be happy. -That's true.
稍微装傻一下也没关系
There's nothing wrong with dying a little inside
那样才能取得共识
so you can meet in the middle.
-老公，你把我挤开了 -我想让她看到我
-Honey, you're pushing me out. -I wanna make sure I can be seen.
-最好她能同时看到 -要挂了，有事要忙
-Well, if she could see both of us. -Gotta go. Work to do.
-掰，宝贝 -一切都会没事的
-Bye, bun-bun. -Everything's gonna be fine.
你们只缺新案子 -知道了，爱你们
- You two just need a new case. - Got it. Love you.
-不如去找那只犬羚吧 -掰
-Maybe try to find that dik-dik. -Bye.
幸运大转盘
Squeal of Fortune!
（鲍伯艾格气象时间）
明天天气还是老样子，什么都有
Tomorrow's weather is, again, everything.
…宣布
...to announce that
期待已久的极地区扩建工程即将开始
the long-awaited Tundratown expansion will be starting soon.
居民对社区未来的担忧仍持续升高
Residents continue to raise concerns about the future of their neighborhood.
但今晚…
But tonight
（有默契还是差异太大？）
我们先放下彼此的不同
we put our differences aside
好好欢庆建城百年庆典
and celebrate at the Zootennial gala,
百年来，在恶名昭彰的爬虫类攻击后
where the Lynxley Journal will be on display for the first time in a century,
厉家手记将首次公开展出
following an infamous reptile attack.
厉家手记中包含括气候墙的专利蓝图
The Lynxley Journal, containing the patented weather wall plans,
(阿慕斯波许外烩)
原作者是厉班瑟，他让…
was originally written by Ebenezer Lynxley, bringing the whole...
同一家外烩公司
Same catering company.
厉家手记
The Lynxley journal.
（祖歌，厉家手记的历史）
（陆龟与蛇的手记恩怨）
（鳞甲怪谭）
冷知识
Truth bomb!
气候墙一百周年
The 100th anniversary of the weather walls
也是动物方城市唯一一次
is also the 100th anniversary
蛇攻击事件的一百周年
of Zootopia's only snake attack.
被害者是一只陆龟
The victim? A tortoise.
这名厉家的女佣想阻止
The Lynxley family maid
毒蛇偷窃厉家手记
who was fanged while stopping a venomous snake
被毒牙咬中
from stealing the Lynxley Journal.
动物方城市从此没再看过蛇
No one has seen a snake in Zootopia since.
但我相信有一条会回来
But I'm convinced one will return.
我唯一的疑问是
My only question is,
他会穿着半条裤子
is he gonna be wearing half-a-pants
还是一只长袜？
or one long sock?
你说：「正义已死」
- You say, "Justice is dead."
我说：「才怪」
I say, "Neigh!"
唉唷，这么快就想我啦？
Well, well, you miss me already, huh?
有蛇皮的厢型车跟办庆典外烩的
The stolen van with the snake skin is from the same catering company
是同一家公司
that's working the gala.
还在研究你的搭档书吗？
This is you studying your partner book?
听我说，以前毒蛇想偷走厉家手记
Listen to me. Venomous snakes tried to steal the Lynxleys's journal before.
要是他们这次又回来偷呢？
What if they're back in town to steal it again?
蛇已经很久没有踏进动物方城市了
No snake has set foot...in Zootopia in forever, okay?
何况他们又没脚
Even if they had feet.
我们麻烦够多了，萝卜头，披萨送来咯…
Look, we're already in the hot seat, Carrots, and pizza's here. Gotta go--
要是庆典发生蛇咬事件，我们却不管
If there's a fanging at the gala and we do nothing to stop it,
就是没做好分内工作…
then we are not doing our jobs...
好恶，难怪你打死不邀我来
Yikes. No wonder you never invite me over.
狐狸都独来独往
Foxes are solitary.
况且，我们去了，你却搞错
And, look, we go and you're wrong,
牛老大会叫我们拆伙
Chief Beef will split us up.
不快点建功，证明我们是好搭档
And if we don't get a win soon and prove we're great partners,
局长还是会拆散我们
the chief will split us up anyway.
巡巡周围，探探情况
Check the perimeter. Snoop a little.
没发现，就撤
We find nothing, we bail.
要是我猜对了
But if I'm right,
就不会有人质疑我们适不适合搭档
no one will question whether you and I belong together again.
不去不行
We need this.
好吧
Fine.
不过，还是得通过安检
But we'll still have to get through security,
狐狸和兔子很难混进那种高级场合
and in fancy town, a fox and a bunny won't exactly blend in.
所以我们要变装卧底
That's why we'll be undercover!
还是你开车啊
See you're still in the driver's seat. Whoa!
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turning the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
一起来，一起来，一起唱
Here we go! Here we go! Let's go!
动物方城市，大声喊
Zootopia, let me hear ya!
生活在疯狂世界，竞争又仓促
♪ We live in a crazy world Caught up in a rat race ♪
水泥丛林生活有时失常
♪ Concrete jungle life Is sometimes a mad place ♪
狂野的一日结束，你和我在一起
♪ It's you and me together At the end of a wild day ♪
不要压抑不语，释放你的精力
♪ Don't keep it all bottled up And release your energy ♪
（建城百年庆典）
为了庆祝，我们齐聚一堂
♪ Only reason we are here Is to celebrate ♪
在这里人人都能出人头地
♪ In a place where anyone Can be anything ♪
珍惜这一刻，别让它流逝
♪ Hold on to this moment Don't let it fade away ♪
宝贝，音乐继续播送
♪ Baby Keep the music playin' ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
来吧，保持下去
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun if You're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
猫爱追光，居然没想到
Ah, cats and lights. I know better.
动物园
♪ A zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
马市长抵达现场了
Mayor Winddancer has arrived...
他也是复仇三部曲《反对者》主角
...star of the revenge trilogy, The Neigh-sayer.
请不要拍照
No pictures, please.
拜托，是我耶
Come on. It's me.
一张，再一张，再来一张
And that, and that one, and then this one.
厉先生，何时开始扩建极地区？
Mr. Lynxley, when will you begin the Tundratown expansion?
-走吧，爸 -好好享受这场派对
-Come on, Dad. -Have a wonderful time at the party.
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun if You're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turning the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
（阿慕斯波许外烩）
没有雪
No snow.
这辆比较热
This one's warmer.
爬虫类在极地区可能需要热气保暖
A reptile in Tundratown might need that to survive the cold.
我的天，有一只
- Oh, my God. A viper!
一支雨刷，对吧？
A "vindow viper." Ja.
后门开着
Back door ajar.
谁都可能让门开着
Anyone could have left it like that.
你说「探探情况」，不是非法闯…
And you said, "Snoop a little,"
天啊
not break and enter-- Oh, God!
反正都得进屋，懂了
Oh, we were always going inside. Got it.
默契你说了算
Same page means your page.
这叫说话的艺术，亲爱的
It's called a hustle, sweetheart.
你在这换装，我到车上换
You change out here. I get the van.
建城百年庆典嘛
It's the Zootennial Gala.
兔子有备而来
A bunny comes prepared.
我常梦想着潜入这种地方
You know, I used to dream of infiltrating a place like this.
其实，你这个点子不算太烂
You know, this is not your worst idea.
哇，听起来像夸奖呢
Wow, that was almost a compliment.
最烂的点子是把耳朵弄成那样
Your worst idea is what you did with your ears.
好吧
All right.
欢迎莅临建城百年庆典
Welcome to the Zootennial Gala...
原始厉家手记公开展出
...featuring the original Lynxley Journal.
蛇为什么会想偷一本旧书？
Why would a snake wanna steal some old book anyway?
不晓得
I don't know.
不过谁也别想偷，我们会保护它
But no one is gonna steal it, because we are here to protect it.
（建城百年庆典）
（私宅，管制区）
手记在管制区，好
The journal is in the reserved section. Okay.
走吧
Come on.
不要急
Slow down.
想混进去？闷头冲是行不通的
You want to fit in? Commando is not gonna cut it.
不只服装要像，好吗？
It's not just the clothes, m'kay?
重点在气场
It is the vibe.
你们好，嘿，驼峰真漂亮
Good to see ya. Hey, real nice humps.
真貂皮吗？这是真狐狸皮
Oh, is that real mink? This is real fox.
你常受邀来这种场合吗？
Get invited to a lot of these?
受邀？没有
Mmm. Invited? No.
但来蹭名流是有别的原因
But there's other reasons to hob knob.
夫人，不好意思，这是你的吗？
Madam, excuse me. Is this yours?
是啊
Why, yes.
我帮你
- Well, allow me.
好精明的狐狸
Clever fox.
那里
Ooh, there!
我认为保全不够多
I don't think it has enough guards.
我凑过去看看，帮我把风
I'll get a closer look. Watch my six.
蛮牛来了
Uh-oh. Bogo alert.
（原始专利，授与厉班瑟）
封面材质是金属
Cover's made of metal.
粗鲁的牛牛也进场了
Gruffalo Buffalo has joined the mix.
三点钟方向
Three o'clock.
不好意思，真抱歉 -不，抱歉
- Oh! Excuse me. I am so sorry. - Oh! Oh, no. Sorry.
我帮你…不对
Here, lemme just... Oh, nope.
这是你的，抱歉
That belongs to you. I apologize.
天啊，他讨厌我
Oh, gosh. He hates me.
给你
Here.
你救了我
Ah! You're my hero.
我喜欢为各种状况做好准备
Well, just like to be prepared for any possible scenario.
派对上说这种话并不奇怪
Which is not a weird thing to say at a party.
我刚才用那家伙的尾巴擦，所以…
Well, I just mopped a spill with that guy's tail, so...
宝!
Paw!
宝柏，我是宝柏，你好
Uh, Pawbert. I am Pawbert. Hi.
茱蒂，我是哈茱蒂
Judy. I'm Judy Hopps.
搞什么猪猪？
Argh! What the pork?
很高兴认识你，茱蒂
Well, 'tis nice to meet you, Judy...
等等，哈茱蒂？那个哈茱蒂？
Wait. Judy Hopps? The Judy Hopps?
这是你精心策划的吗？
Are you working this?
你显然有精心打扮
I mean, you're clearly working it.
不过，你在办案吗？
But are you actually working this?
没有…只是直觉啦
Uh, no. I'm actually...Well, it's just a hunch.
要保护那个
...protecting that.
好，我认为保全不够多
Good. I don't think it has enough guards.
那是我的哏
Uh, that was my joke.
这里没动静
Yeah, and there's nothing here.
我们收工吧
Let's call it a night.
哈同学？
Hopps?
我们应该…
Well, we should...
很高兴认识你
It was nice to meet you.
我也是
Yes, and you.
大快朵颐
Uh, bon appétit.
要是你决定吃东西，祝大快朵颐
If, at any point tonight, you choose to eat, bon appétit then.
你应该待在台下，宝柏
You're supposed to be off stage, Pawbert.
对啊，快下台，宝柏
Yeah, get off stage, Pawbert.
等等，你是…
Wait, are you...
对，我是厉家人
Yeah, I am a Lynxley.
或者说，我正在努力
Or, you know, I'm trying to be.
让开，宝柏
Now, Pawbert.
走吧，爸比
Come on, Papi.
-有我在，爸，放心 -不，我来
-I got you, Pa. Don't you worry. -No, I have him. I have him.
好吧，我们赶快开始
All right, let's get this thing started.
欢迎莅临建城百年庆典
Welcome to the Zootennial Gala.
哈同学，我想我可能…
Hey, Hopps. I think I might actually...
我发现了线索
I think I've got something.
看看你们
Ah. Look at you all.
见到你们真好
Good to see ya.
我很荣幸介绍第三代深具远见…
It is with great pleasure that I introduce the third-generation visionary...
萝卜头，听得到吗？我发现一条路径
Carrots, can you hear me? I have a trail.
延续我们这城市的传统
...who has continued the legacy of our great city,
厉弥顿
Milton Lynxley.
-谢谢，非常感谢 -萝卜头
- Thank you. Thank you very much. - Carrots. Carrots.
你来这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
局长，她是对的
Chief, she was right.
你完了，你们都完了 -等等
- You're done. You're both done. - Wait. No, no.
我祖父有个梦想
My grandpa had a dream
为所有动物打造一座城市
to build a city for all animals.
尼克？
Nick?
让大家真正共存共荣
To truly be better together.
有蛇!
There's a snake!
蛇…
Snake, snake, snake!
跑，斑宝，跑
Go, bro, go.
你给我记住，斑马
I will remember you, zebra.
茱蒂…
Judy. Judy!
我就知道
I knew it!
别跑
Stop!
拜托，你没必要伤害他
Please. You don't have to hurt him.
伤害他？
Hurt him?
蛇…从不伤害任何人
Snakes never hurt anyone.
我们不是坏人
We aren't the bad guys.
他们才是
They are.
这本手记里的秘密能够证明
And this journal holds the secret that will prove it.
我必须证明，拜托
I have to prove it. Please.
这是我们厘清事实唯一的机会
This is our only chance to set things right.
到时候
And when I do,
我的家人就终于能回家了
my family will finally be able to come home.
-不 -我来了
- Oh, no! - I am here.
哈胡双雄，梦幻团队
Hopps and Wilde... ...dream team.
逮到他了，或是她
We got him. Or her.
爬虫类，雌雄莫辨
Reptiles, it's, like, who knows?
警察马上就来了
The cops are right behind us.
杀了这条蛇
Kill the snake.
我们烧掉手记
We'll burn the journal.
他想拿走，就代表它有危险
If he wants it, it's dangerous.
你们两个提出报告，说他攻击我们
And then you two will file a report that he attacked us,
而且不准泄漏出去
and you will keep your mouths shut.
让开
Step aside.
快灭火
Put out the fire!
-萝卜头，快走 -帮我救他
- Carrots, come on. - Help me save him.
-萝卜头，我们得… -尼克
- Carrots, we need-- - Nick.
好冷…
Cold! Cold!
不！
No!
局长
Chief.
他不会有事的
He'll be okay.
用血清，用抗毒血清就能救他
Antivenom. He can be saved with antivenom.
哈茱蒂，你做了什么？ -不，霍队长
Hopps, what did you do? - No, Hogg-- Hoggbottom.
他们在帮那条蛇，想杀了局长
They're helping the snake. They're trying to kill the chief!
-霍队长，没有 -支援，我需要支援
- Hoggbottom, no. Please. - Backup! I need backup!
听我的，我们走 -等等…
- My page. Let's go. - Wait, wait, wait.
我需要手记，可能还要毛衣
I need the journal and probably a sweater.
好冷
Cold.
给我趴下 -等等
- On the ground. - Wait.
喂 -下次我们待在家里？
- Oi! - Next time, we stay home?
不准动
Don't you move.
不，拦住他们
No. Stop them!
喂 -快走
- Oi! - Come on.
别跑 -快
- Stop! - Come on!
别跑
Stop!
我真的只是一只傻兔子
I really am just a dumb bunny.
不小心录到，你说的，不是我
Accident. Your words, not mine.
塞进后车厢
Put 'em in the trunk.
（最新消息）
极地区发生恐怖事件
"Ter-roar" in Tundratown.
庆典上有蛇咬事件
A fanging at the fiesta.
一条毒蛇攻击厉氏家族
A howl-a at the gala as a venomous snake attacks the founding family.
更惊人的是那条蛇的帮凶
More shocking, the snake was aided
是陷入困境的ZPD警员胡尼克跟哈茱蒂
by embattled ZPD officers Nicholas Wilde and Judy Hopps.
（逃亡兔狐警员与蛇罪犯合作）
三名嫌犯都涉及警察局长
All three now suspects in the tragic fanging
悲惨的蛇咬事件，被认为极度危险
of Zootopia's chief of police and considered extremely dangerous.
（在逃嫌犯）
蛮牛局长…死了
Chief Bogo...is dead.
很高兴我不必说这句话
Those are words I'm glad I don't have to say.
但可能快了
I might have to soon.
医生有点担心
The doctors are a little weirded out, but
但今晚发生的事绝对不是马戏
what has happened tonight was more than horseplay.
我们…
Uh, we, uh...
一定要逮捕那条蛇
We're gonna take that snake down.
还有狐狸和那只兔子
And the fox and that rabbit!
你知道他们已经毁了几位市长吗？
Do you know how many mayors they've already destroyed?
一、二…我想到两个
One, two... I got up to two.
你想当第三个吗？
Would you like to be "three"?
我要除掉他们
I want them gone.
不是有…法律吗？
But aren't there... laws?
这句话我只说一次，小马哥
I will say this once, Brian.
你要把手记拿回来，并埋了他们
You will retrieve the journal and bury them.
难道我选错了市长吗？
Or maybe I chose the wrong mayor.
我是不是选错市长了？
Did I choose the wrong mayor?
（警察）
（妈和爸）
（拒绝来电）
（我们看到新闻了）
（哎呀，我是说…）
（天啊，我是说…）
（我是爸）
（妈接手…）
（我们很担心你）
嘿
Hey.
他们会优先追踪手机
The phone is the first thing they'll track.
抱歉，我从来没因为犯法逃亡过
Sorry. I have never been on the run from the law before.
是啊
Yeah. Boy.
我们好像不该到庆典去，对吧？
It's almost like we shouldn't have gone to that gala, huh?
好，以前都听你的
Okie doke. We already did it your way.
碰到B老大，改听我的
With Mr. Big, we do it mine.
这时出身底层的搭档就能派上用场
This is where having a partner from the underworld is really gonna pay off.
雷蒙！这位是凯…
Raymond! And is that Kev...
（合法皮包公司）
欢迎光临我的仓库
Welcome to my warehouse.
天啊，我爱你的礼服
Oh, my God, I love your dress.
谢谢
Oh! Thank you.
露露跟我现在是家族事业的合伙人
Fru Fru and I are now equal partners in the family business.
她为犯罪和时尚带来绝妙的点子
She brings wonderful ideas for crime and for fashion
我则有更多时间做最重要的事
while I get more time to focus on what matters most:
当小茱蒂的阿公
being grandpapa to my little Judith.
亲我的戒指
Kiss my ring.
-马上亲戒指 -现在就亲，快亲
-Kiss the stinkin' ring right now! -You kiss it right now! Kiss it!
阿公，你说我们要用威斯顿先生做消波块
Nonno, you said we were gonna make cement shoes for Mr. Weaselton.
好孩子
Oh, that's my girl.
小孩长得好快
They grow up so fast.
闭嘴，狐狸 -你话太多了
- You shut your mouth, fox! - You run your mouth too much!
总之，你们有麻烦了
Anyways, you're in trouble.
我们喜欢你们其中一个
And we like one of yas,
所以我们会帮忙
so we're here to help.
新衣服，新身份
New clothes. New identities.
出城卡车一小时后出发
Truck out of town leaves in an hour.
你开罚单的车已经解决了
And your meter maid cart is taken care of.
我想你们误会了
I think you misunderstand.
我们被厉家陷害，而一条无辜的蛇…
We've been framed by the lynxes. And an innocent snake needs...
茱蒂，厉家心狠手辣，没有道德底线
Judy, the lynxes are killers...and they have no honor.
这次极地区扩建让他们更危险
And this Tundratown expansion only makes them more dangerous.
领域性动物为了土地会不择手段
Territorial animals will do anything for more land.
你们卷入的事如果威胁到他们的计划
So, if whatever you're tangled up in threatens their plans,
你们就死定了
you're dead.
别跟山猫斗，快逃
You don't fight the cats. You leave.
老大，我知道你想保护我们
Sir, I know you're trying to look out for us.
可是我们宣誓过要保护城市
But we took an oath to protect this city.
正义不会逃跑
And justice doesn't run.
我代表我自己胡瑞克
On behalf of myself, "Rick Wilde,"
和蔡楚蒂小姐
and "Miss Trudy Cabbagepatch,"
感谢你的逃亡卡车和…
we thank you for your truck to salvation and-- Ow!
我们不能接受你的好意
We cannot accept your offer.
我们要帮那条蛇
We are helping that snake.
你真是会滥用「我们」
Boy, you're really tossing that "we" around.
蛇可能被陷害，说他们咬了陆龟
Snakes may have been framed for the fanging of that tortoise.
你知道是什么原因吗？
Do you have any idea why?
还是怎么用这本书来证明？
Or how this book could prove it?
我知道就好了
I wish I did.
但要是牵扯到蛇
But if it has to do with snakes,
你们最好去找爬虫类谈
your best bet is talking to a reptile.
你有认识吗？
Do you know any?
几乎没人认识
Almost no one does.
他们不跟大家来往，躲在沼泽市场
They keep to themselves, hide out in Marsh Market.
你们还是能找到他们
But you can still find 'em.
只是需要爬虫类专家
You just need a reptile expert.
一个能带路的在地居民
Someone local who knows where to go.
你们运气好，我认识一位
Lucky for you, I met someone.
她是播客主持人
She runs a podcast!
（播客主聂狸宝）
不，蔡楚蒂，胡瑞克不答应
No, no. Trudy Cabbagepatch, Rick Wilde says no.
哦耶！
Oh, yeah!
（树枝达人）
哈胡双雄在逃亡，秘密侦查我在行
If Hopps and Wilde are on the lam, subtle sleuthin' 'tis my jam.
当心木刺
Woo! Mind the splinters.
你们找对河狸了
Oh, you called the right beaver.
想跟爬虫类谈，找我就对了
If you wanna talk to a reptile, I am your gal.
想找鹿角兔谈的话…
Also, if you need to talk to a jackalope,
他们是真的啦，妈
which are real, Mom!
不好意思，内部会议
Excuse us. Team meeting.
反对找河狸
Vetoing the beave.
来投票：赞成保住小命
New vote: All in favor of "Truck to Being Alive
低调避风头的请举手，毕竟…
and Laying Low Till This Blows Over-ville"? I mean...
哈胡双雄不会半途而废
Hopps and Wilde do not bail on a case.
可是她秀斗
But she's crazy.
可能吃太多铅笔，铅中毒了
Probably lead poisoning from eating too many pencils.
你有认识爬虫类，知道这里的秘密
Do you know a reptile who can tell us the hidden secret in here,
或是厉家为何要陷害蛇吗？
or why the lynxes framed the snakes?
24小时，到明天日出
Twenty-four hours. Sunrise tomorrow.
没结果就去避风头，我从此改名蔡茱蒂
If we strike out, then we go into hiding, and "Judy Cabbagepatch" it is.
是蔡楚蒂，还有安全暗号是「椰子」
It's "Trudy" Cabbagepatch, and the safe word is "coconut."
在阴暗潮湿的地下通道里，他们上了车
In the darkness of a dank underpass, they stepped into the vehicle,
浑然不觉自己的人生即将改变
not realizing their lives were about to change.
因为…我们要去见爬虫类？
Because we're gonna meet a reptile?
因为你们就要成为
Because you're about to be best buds
聂狸宝的好麻吉
with Nibbles Maplestick!
两个能跳舞，三个能成虎
Takes two to tango, but a threesome to be somethin'.
去帮你们找爬虫类，前进沼泽
Let's find you a reptile and romp the swamp.
（欢迎莅临沼泽市场，方城市之珠）
吸口气!
Breathe it in!
要是有爬虫类知道那本书的秘密
Now, if any reptile would know
蛇为何要偷走它…
the secret of that book and why the snake wants it...
嘿，强尼！
Hey, Johnny!
不！不！\M- Oh, no!
就是我的蜥蜴老友何力蜥
...it's my old lizard friend, Jesús.
蜥蜴为什么躲在这里？
Why would a lizard hide here?
（蓝线）
在动物方城市建造时
Well, when Zootopia was founded,
这一带就跟其他地区切割开来
the whole neighborhood got cut off from the rest of the town.
成了自治区
Kinda on our own here.
所以爬虫类才喜欢
Yeah, that's probably why reptiles like it.
爱怎样就怎样
They can just do their thing.
加上只有这里
Plus, it's the only place in town
没人管你穿衣不穿裤
you can get away with wearing a shirt and no pants.
听啃木头的导览介绍，帅啊
Loving tour time with Woodchuckles. Great call.
我们需要她 -是啊，在头上开洞算了
- We need her. - Oh, yeah. Like a hole in the head.
别对号入座
Bad timing. Hmm.
好，到何力蜥的藏身处得搭渡轮
Okay, to get to Jesús's hideout, we gotta take a ferry.
在地人我来搞定
Just let me handle the locals.
他们对外地来的防卫心比较重
Water folk tend to be a little standoffish around landies.
我12岁就在街头讨生活
Well, I've been hustling the streets since I was 12.
我能跟杂耍海豹打交道
I think I can handle a juggling seal.
是海狮
Sea lion.
他外地来的
He's not from around here.
该给还是得给
- But coin's a coin.
不行，硬币有窒息风险
Oh, no. Change... ...is a choking hazard.
好吧，无心之过
- Well, honest mistake.
（禁止触碰）
别这么做
Do not do that!
还是让狸宝应付吧
Let's let Nibbles handle this.
谢谢你，茱蒂
Thank you, Judith.
和美丽的海洋生物打交道
Conversing with these beautiful sea creatures
就像跟个性不同的朋友聊天
is like talking to anyone a little different.
只要放开心胸，彼此尊重就行了
Just takes open and respectful communication.
（需要服务请摇铃）
- 嘿，叭噗 - 嘿，叭噗
- Heya, bub. - Hey, bub.
- Heya, bub, hey. - Hey, bub, heya.
- 叭噗叭噗 -叭噗叭噗
- Bubba, bubba, bubba. - Bubba, bubba, bubba.
嘿，叭噗 - 嘿，叭噗叭噗
- Heya, bub. - Hey, bub. Hey, bub, bub.
- 嘿，叭噗 - 嘿，叭噗
- Heya, bub. Bubby, bub. - Hey, bub. Hey, bub. Hey, ho.
- Heya, bub, bub. - Hey, bub.
有看到何力蜥？
Seen Jesús?
有
Yup.
现在真的得出城了
And now we leave town.
真的要谢谢你
Thank you for this.
一周纪念快乐
Happy anniversary.
你们的纪念日？
It's your anniversary?
就在今夜
♪ This is the night ♪
美丽的一夜
♪ It's a beautiful night ♪
我们叫它贝拉诺特
- ♪ And we call it bella notte ♪
这下怎么找到他们？
How are we gonna find them now?
谢了，海豹
- Thanks, seal.
朋友，不…
Friend. No, no, no!
对不起…
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
再过去一点点
Just a little farther.
何力蜥跟你们需要的答案
Jesús and all the answers you'll ever need
就在这条可怕黑暗的走道尽头
are, uh, right here at the end of this very scary, dark hallway.
天啊，这比坐在南方岛屿的沙滩上
Boy, this is so much better
啜饮树袋熊调酒
than sitting on a beach on Outback Island,
好玩多了
sipping piña koalas.
我们不能一走了之
Hmm. We are not skipping town
外头有一条无辜的蛇需要我们
when there is an innocent snake out there who needs us.
他有朋友帮忙，那个机车骑士
He's got help: his motorcycle buddy.
你怪怪的，到底怎么了？
You are acting weird. What is your problem?
第一，你强迫我
Well, A, you railroaded me.
第二
And B...
如果你真想知道
...if you must know,
我对爬虫类没好感
I have an aversion to reptiles.
什么？
What?
我不舒服让你觉得好笑吗？
Oh, is my discomfort hilarious to you?
不，对不起，说得对，我们是搭档
No, you're... I'm sorry. You're right, we are partners.
每当我觉得不舒服
And whenever I'm uncomfortable,
你总是顾虑到我的感受
you are always very considerate of my feelings.
小心，蛇皮
Look out! Snake skin!
滑下去了…抓住栏杆
I'm slipping! I'm slipping! Hold the rail!
我抓住了 -抓好…
- I'm holding the rail. - Hold it. Hold it.
别拉我耳朵 -抓住栏杆
- Stop pulling my ears! - Hold the rail.
千万别拉兔耳朵
Never pull a bunny's ears!
抓住栏杆 -千万别拉兔耳朵
- Hold the rail. - Never pull a bunny's ears!
真正让人不懂的
I think the real mystery
是你们怎么能联手破案
is how you two ever solved anything.
不说了，去听听何力蜥对手记的说法
Anyhoo, let's see what Jesús has to say about your journal.
要是他请吃东西，要接受
Oh, and if he offers you food, accept.
拒绝就表示对他们全体不尊重
Declining is a sign of disrespect, to all of them.
他们全体？
"All of them"?
上菜了
Order up.
再来一杯
Hey, another drink.
好温暖
So warm.
哎呀
Whoops.
不！
No!
留着
Keep it.
何力蜥
Jesús!
向你介绍我朋友，这是茱蒂和尼克
Allow me to introduce my friends. This is Judith and Nicholas.
通缉犯
They are wanted fugitives
在调查一桩蛇悬案，还得想办法不送命
investigating a snake mystery and trying not to get murdered.
我们能坐吗？
May we sit?
好吧
Oh. Okay.
我不吃，但他们好像很饿
Oh, I'm good, but these guys look hungry.
谢谢你愿意见我们
Thank you for meeting with us.
我们相信蛇因为手记的内容被陷害
We believe snakes were framed for something in this journal,
说不定跟… -先吃，再谈
- perhaps pertaining to... - Eat first, talk second.
各位，他们吃了
Hey, guys. They ate it!
看他们的表情
Look at their faces.
我才不吃蛆蛆
I don't eat grubs.
小兄弟，拿司康来
Hermano, get me a scone!
好吧
Okay, okay.
金属书皮
Metal cover.
什么意思？
And what does that mean?
意思是
It means
很高级
it's fancy.
也表示，你们要找的秘密
It also means the secret you're looking for
应该就在书皮上
is probably right on the cover.
毒蛇就是有办法看穿金属
Somehow vipers can see things in the metal,
上了颜料都没问题
even under the paint.
这是厉班瑟写的气候墙原始手记
This is Ebenezer Lynxley's original journal for the weather walls.
有什么秘密得瞒着一条蛇？
Why would he hide a secret for a snake?
不知道
I don't know.
但一定很重要，有陆龟为了它送命
But it must have been big, 'cause a tortoise died for it.
我猜她一定死得很慢
I am guessing that it was a slow death.
蛇咬不只改变大家对蛇的看法
The fanging didn't just change how folks saw snakes.
哺乳类也不再信任爬虫类了
No mammals trusted any reptile after that.
（爬虫类：是敌是友？）
所以我们都离开了
That's why we all left.
就在那时厉家第一次扩建极地区
And that's when the Lynxleys expanded Tundratown the first time.
现在又来了
And it's happening again.
极地区将延伸到这里
The expansion is going here.
沼泽市场会被冰雪覆盖
Marsh Market will be buried in snow.
我们都会被逼走
We'll all get pushed out.
厉家会得到更多土地
Those lynxes will get more land,
谁也没办法阻止他们
and there's no way to stop 'em.
要是藏在手记的秘密可以呢？
What if the secret hidden in here could?
那我会说
Then I would say
拥有它会让你们陷入极大的危险
holding it puts the two of you in grave danger.
他们跟踪你们？
They tracked you?
完蛋
Whoops.
是ZPD！
It's the ZPD!
快跑
Run!
Leave the tails!
跟我来，快点
Follow me. Come on!
等等，你为什么要帮我们？
Wait. Why are you helping us?
你们救过这座城市
You two saved the city once.
应该能再救一次
I reckon you can save it again.
到时候
And when you do,
也许大家会明白，我们没那么不同
maybe everyone will see we ain't that different.
别动 -对，别动
- Freeze! - Yeah, freeze!
真抱歉，这是我家人回家的唯一机会
I'm really sorry. But this is my family's only chance to come home.
等等，我们想帮忙
Wait. We wanna help.
等等…
Wait. Wait.
回来
Come back!
没有路，从码头走
There's no path. Take the docks!
什么…萝卜头
Wha-- Carrots!
等等，我们相信你
Wait! We believe you!
尼克！快点
Nick! Come on! Come on!
（水管站）
抓住
Grab it!
喂
Hey!
看到他们了，往水管去了
I got eyes on them. They're heading for the tubes!
追捕中
In pursuit.
- 嘿，叭噗
Hey, bubba.
- 嘿，叭噗 - 嘿，叭噗
- Hey, bub. - Hey, bub.
快走
Go!
- 嘿，叭噗 - 嘿，叭噗
- Hey, bub. - Hey, bub.
掰掰
- Bub-bye. - Hey, Bub.
掰掰 -掰掰
- Bub-bye. - Bub-bye.
掰掰，掰
Bub-bye. Bye.
- 嘿，叭噗 -掰掰
- Hey, bub. - Bub-bye.
专业撇步，如果他往红线方向冲
Pro tip! If he goes for the red line,
千万别跟过去
do not follow!
你们会没气的
You will run out of air!
加油，我爱你们
Good luck! I love you!
抱歉
Sorry.
深水炸弹!
Cannonball!
（危险！陆上动物勿入）
那是红线…
That's a red line. Red line!
你们会没气的，椰子！椰子！
You're going to run out of air! Coconut! Coconut!
你需要的我都有
Anything you need, I got 'em.
（魔宫传奇，魔马奇缘，漂浮奇缘12）
续集、前传、外传
Sequels, prequels, requels.
谁说影视业一泻千里？
Who says the industry's going down the tubes?
（买一送一）
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
对，还好
Yeah. Yes.
你呢？
Uh, you?
我…
I... Well, I've...
我觉得…
I feel like some...
可能应该道个歉
some "sorries," uh, may be in order.
尼克，没关系
Nick, it's okay.
我知道你不是故意要追丢他的
I know you didn't want to lose him on purpose.
不是我道歉，不是
Oh, not me sorry. No, no.
是你道歉
You sorry.
现在好像没办法找到他或阻止厉家
Well, now we kinda have no way to find him or stop the lynxes,
所以我可不这么认为
so agree to disagree.
可是…
But...
我们还活着
we are alive.
要是找不到他，算了
So if we can't find him, that's great.
我们可以找辆卡车离开
What we can find is a truck out of here.
一盒旧火柴，真有用啊
Box of old matches. Helpful.
蔡楚蒂，该离开了，玩完了
Trudy Cabbagepatch, leaving town. We're done.
唷得雷嘻嗬
Yodelayheehoo!
你们竟然在这个地方
Ah, dis is veird place for you to be.
对，非常奇怪
Ja, very veird.
他们从水管掉出来
Ach, zey fell out of ze tube.
好吧，我们叫警察来帮忙
Okay, ve vill call police to help!
不用，不…我们没事
Nope! No, no, we're fine.
对，我们正好要离开
Yep, we were just leaving town.
对了，你们知道这条水管通到哪吗？
Actually, um, do you happen to know where this tube goes?
歌本哈芬 -对，歌本哈芬
- Oh, Copenhoofen. - Ja, ist Copenhoofen.
知道了，谢…
- Got it. Thank y--
你吃太多了，这样子不行啦
Oh, you chew too much. This is not okay!
你们在哪里找到这些花的？
Where did... Where did you find these flowers?
爱之花吗？在这座山的山顶
Oh, the Liebenflower? Ze tippity-top of ze mountain.
它们只长在那上面
Uh, zis is ze only place zey grow.
惨了
Oh, boy.
上…
- Is...
上面还有其他东西吗？
Uh, is there anything else up there?
没有，当然没有 -有
- Nope, there sure isn't. - Oh, ja.
老蜜月木屋
Old Honeymoon Lodge.
不过关闭很久了，有蛇躲在里面
But is closed for long time. Was hideout for snakes.
蜜月木屋
Honeymoon Lodge.
要怎么过去？
How...How do you reach it?
游客会从歌本哈芬搭电车
Oh, tourists take ze tram from Copenhoofen,
但攀绳比较快
but ze rope is faster.
祝好运，好好享受蜜月木屋
Good luck! Have fun at ze Honeymoon Lodge!
谢谢
Thank you!
这个秘密和爬虫类离开有什么关系？
What does the secret have to do with the reptiles leaving town?
当初为何藏在手记里？
How did it get hidden in the journal in the first place?
慢点好吗？
Will you slow down?
你想霍队长和ZPD
How long do you think it's going to be
多久会查出我们的下落？
before Hoggbottom and the ZPD figure out where we are?
无论如何，我们应该再快一点
If anything, we should be going faster.
就像我常说的…
As I always say...
我真的只是一只傻兔子
I really am just a dumb bunny.
尼克…
Nick...
我…真的只是…
I-- I-- I-- I-- I really am
傻…兔子
ju-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb bunny.
只是一只傻…兔子
Just dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb-- dumb bunny.
这个礼物象征我们的搭档关系
This was a gift to symbolize our partnership,
这时候拿来用很不恰当
and it is not appropriate for this moment.
不，我只是把一些想法记下来
Oh, no, I was just...hoping to jot down some ideas
以后能刻在我们墓碑上
for what we will put on our tombstones.
我先说，「是他的搭档害的」
I'll start. "His partner did it."
你为什么就不能好好说话？
What happened to you that you can't just have a normal conversation?
我要留着跟我咨询师说
I will save that for my therapy animal.
- 对，你需要一位咨询师 - 对
- Yeah, you need a therapy animal. - Oh, yeah.
而你需要一群咨询师
Well, you need a herd of therapy animals.
对，你还要从外地
Yeah. You need a whole migration
调一整批咨询师来
of therapy animals.
萝卜头？
Carrots?
嘿，萝卜头？
Hey, Carrots?
萝卜头？
Uh, Carrots?
萝卜头
Carrots!
（厉班瑟对全体动物的计划）
（因蛇攻击受阻）
（极地区扩建）
（爬虫区在哪？）
原本有一整个爬虫类社区
There was a whole reptile neighborhood.
他们的家…
Their home...
被厉家铲除了
The lynxes just erased it.
这是他们干的
This is what they do.
我们该走了
We have to go.
用谎言逼走动物，牟取更多利益
They push animals out with lies so they can have more.
我们该走了，萝卜头，快点
We gotta go. Carrots, we gotta go!
-那条蛇想证明这个 -ZPD来了
-That's what the snake's trying to prove. -The ZPD is here.
什么？
What?
没人会相信我们，要有证据
No one will believe us. Not without proof.
别管了，他们不只会逮捕我们
Leave it. They aren't gonna just arrest us.
厉家还要我们死
The lynxes want us dead.
我们需要它来破案
We need it to solve the case.
茱蒂 -我们非破案不可
- Judy, just... - We have to solve the case.
尼克 -我不在乎这个案子
- Nick... - I don't care about the case!
茱蒂，这不值得送命
Judy, it's not worth dying for.
要是没人挺身而出
The world will never be a better place
世界永远不会变好
if no one is brave enough to do the right thing.
世界就是这样，萝卜头
The world is what it is, Carrots,
而且有时候，当英雄…
and sometimes being a hero...
也不会造成改变
it just doesn't make a difference.
我想…
I think, uh...
我想，也许…
I think maybe...
也许我们…
maybe we...
确实不一样
are different.
天啊，我想我杀了一个警察
Oh, my gosh, I think I just took out a cop.
抱歉，长官
Uh. Sorry, sir!
宝柏？ -对…其实
- Pawbert? - Yeah. It's, uh... you know...
我们是好人 -就说她会帮忙
- We're the good guys! - I told you she's helping.
跟我们走
- Come with us.
逮到狐狸了，逮到狐狸了
We have the fox. We have the fox!
他们已经抓到你搭档
They already have your partner.
你不能也被抓
They can't get you too.
拜托，我们能阻止我的家人
Please. We can stop my family.
茱蒂
Judy!
不…
- No, no, no!
抓住你了
I got you.
好，放马过来
All right. Here we go.
什么？
What?
你没死
- You're not dead!
她没死
- She's not dead!
抱歉，抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我刚拿到机车驾照
I just got my motorcycle license.
尼克呢？
Nick?
他们…
They, uh...
他们抓走他了
They caught him.
但在这里，谁都抓不到我们
But out here, no one's gonna catch us.
马立夯市长
Mayor Winddancer.
那只兔子呢？
Where's the bunny?
不知道
I don't know.
不过她是兔子
But, you know, she's a rabbit.
说不定能从你帽子里变出来
So maybe you can pull her out of your hat.
我没戴帽子
I'm not wearing a hat.
他在捉弄你，市长
He's messing with you, sir.
我知道，把他带走
I knew that. Get him out of here.
不
No.
他们在哪，胡先生？
Where are they, Mr. Wilde?
展开扩建工程
Begin the expansion.
冰封沼泽市场
Freeze Marsh Market.
把大家赶走 -什么？
- Flush everyone out. - What? No, you can't--
亲水族跟狐狸一样，都是低等哺乳类
Water folk, like foxes, are lesser mammals.
只要我说他们帮过危险的蛇
If I say they helped a dangerous snake,
谁都不会在乎我们怎么做
no one will care what we do.
你进黑暗牢房吧，胡先生
You're going to a dark cell, Mr. Wilde.
直到你看到搭档死亡的新闻
Just long enough to read the headline of your partner's demise.
当初你该把握机会逃走才对
You should've left town when you had the chance.
爸
Dad.
毛发，应该是帮忙兔子和蛇的同伙
Fur from whoever's helping the bunny and the snake.
去找宝柏
Find Pawbert.
快到我的巢穴了
Almost to me hideout.
蛇该进洞了
Snake in the hole.
好，好
Ooh. Yeah, yeah.
我们会成功的，哈茱蒂
We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
我们会阻止厉家，救你的搭档
We'll stop the Lynxleys and save your partner.
不好意思，你是…
I'm sorry. You are...
盖瑞，佘盖瑞
Oh. Gary. Gary the Snake.
贵姓呢？
And your last name?
佘
De'Snake.
一切都会很顺利的
Everything is gonna be okay.
跟你们搭档感觉好刺激
Teaming up with you is very exciting.
别担心我的毒牙
Ooh! Uh, don't worry about my fang.
我随身带着抗毒血清
I got my own anti-venom pen.
能解蛇毒
Stops the toxin.
把我刺入心脏
Stab me straight into the heart.
欢迎光临我的绿洲
Welcome to my oasis...
远离我的邪恶家族
...away from my evil family.
我喜欢来这里耍废
I like to come here, just kind of veg out.
玩我的猫玩意儿 -哇
- Get with all my cat stuff. - Wow.
不，那是古董 -赞哦
- No! That's actually vintage. - Awesome.
不，你不能碰
No! If you could just not.
不行，拜托不要
- Ooh! - No! No, please don't.
-哇，哺乳类的东西超棒 -天啊，不
- Wow! Mammals get the best stuff. - Oh, my gosh. No.
-这做什么的？ -不要
- What's this do? - Wait, not that.
关掉…
Turn it off. Turn it off. Turn it off. Turn it off.
那我们来看手记好了
So, we should probably get to the journal, hmm?
你们怎么会变成搭档？
How did you become partners?
当我发现庆典要展出这本手记时
Oh, when I found out the journal was going to be on display at the Gala,
我寄匿名信到他家，要求看手记
I sent his family an anonymous letter asking to see it.
幸好他们派宝柏到邮件室工作
Luckily, they make Pawbert work in the mail room,
他先看到信
so he read it first.
我从海外将他走私进来
I got him smuggled in from overseas.
在箱子里待了七天
Seven days in a crate.
但我如果挽救家族名声，就很值得
But if I fix things for my family, it'll be worth it.
到时我们也会救你的搭档
Then we'll fix things for your partner too.
嘿
Hey.
我知道跟我们一起走很难受
I know coming with us was hard,
但我们会救你的搭档
but we're gonna help your partner,
就像我们会救这城市一样
the same way we're gonna help the city.
我们要阻止我家人，让大家知道真相
We stop my family and show everyone the truth.
准备好了吗？
Are you ready?
点火吧
Light the fire.
你知道多少？
How much do you know?
呃，他家人是被陷害的
Well, uh, that his family was framed,
有个秘密藏在金属书皮里
and there's some secret hidden in the metal cover
只有蛇看得见
that only a snake can see.
不是一般的蛇，是能感应热的蝮蛇
Not just any snake, a heat-sensing pit viper.
只要温暖一点就行了
All it takes is a little warmth.
我实在不懂
I just... I don't understand.
你曾祖父的秘密为何要瞒着一条蛇？
Why would your great-grandfather hide a secret for a snake?
他没有
He didn't.
我…
I...
这不是他的手记
It wasn't his journal.
那就是秘密
That's the secret.
创建动物方城市的不是哺乳类
Zootopia wasn't created by a mammal.
而是一条蛇
It was created by a snake.
盖瑞的外曾祖母
Gary's great-grandmother.
她想打造一个
She wanted to make the city a place
所有动物都受到欢迎的城市
where all animals felt welcome.
所以她发明了气候墙来帮助大家
So she invented her weather walls to help everyone.
（原始专利，授与佘艾妮）
她只需要一名投资者
She just needed an investor.
一个合伙人
A partner.
但我曾祖父发现她的构想非常有价值
But when my great-grandfather saw what her idea could be worth...
便密谋把这项计划据为己有
he plotted to steal her plans for himself.
（原始专利，授与厉班瑟）
于是他痛下杀手
So he committed a murder...
杀害自家女佣
his own maid...
嫁祸给盖瑞的外曾祖母
and framed Gary's great-grandmother.
因为她是一条蛇
And because she was a snake,
（爬虫类和哺乳类：不容一市？）
大家都相信他的谎言
everyone believed his lie.
不久，爬虫类受到排挤
Soon, no reptiles were welcome.
过了一段时间
And over time,
我曾祖父将爬虫类社区埋在雪中
my great-grandfather buried the reptile neighborhood in snow.
（佘公馆）
临终时他仍相信
And he died believing
没有人能揭发他的罪行
no one could ever uncover his crimes.
可是…
But...
他错了
he was wrong.
她的原始专利证书被保留下来
Her original patent was saved.
原来你在找这个
That's what you're looking for.
她藏在她家
She hid it in her home.
只要找到她家，就能找到专利证书
Find her home, find her patent.
我们不清楚她的家埋在哪里
We just didn't know where her home was buried
但现在知道了
until now.
我家族的土地？
My family's land?
可是，埋在雪地里，要怎么找？
But under all that snow, how are we gonna find it?
等等
Wait.
钟楼
Clock tower.
她住的爬虫类社区有一座钟楼
Her neighborhood, the reptile neighborhood, had a clock tower.
像灯塔会发光
It lights up like a beacon.
要是没完全掩埋，也许能看到它
If it wasn't fully buried, maybe we could see it.
就能找到她的家
Follow it to her home.
但我曾祖父把电力切断了
Except my great-grandfather turned off the power.
这里有蓝图教我们怎么重新打开
But we have the plans that show us how to turn it back on.
她整个社区的总电力开关是在…
The power switch to her whole neighborhood
原本的控制室里
was in the original control room.
太好了
All right!
它在哪呢？
And where is that?
在全市最古老的墙内
Inside the oldest wall of the city.
沙漠极地区气候墙
The Desert Tundratown weather wall.
我们进去，打开开关
We get inside, turn on that switch,
点亮钟楼
light the clock tower,
就能找到她的家 -就找到她的专利证书
- we find her house. - We find her patent.
那我的家人终于能回家了
And my family is finally coming home.
我们会成功的，哈茱蒂
We will succeed, Judy Hopps.
我们一定会成功
We shall succeed!
（追踪中）
（找到目标）
找到他了
I found him.
通知霍队长
Get me Hoggbottom.
是胡尼克，红牌警察
Ooh! It's Nicholas Wilde. Big-time cop, huh?
我们午餐时间见
I'll see you at the lunch table.
我要把你的尾巴打成结
I'm gonna tie your tail in a knot.
-霍队长 -看什么看，呆瓜？
-Hoggbottom-- -What are you looking at, butthead?
这是误会，我被猞猁陷害
This is a mistake. It's a setup. It's the lynxes.
你听我说，拜托
Listen to me. Please.
我知道我们彼此很不同
I know we have had our differences, right?
但是我一向尊敬你…
But I've always respected you--
你谁都不尊敬
You don't respect anyone.
电话，是厉弥顿
Phone. It's Milton Lynxley.
他查出兔子的位置了
He's got the rabbit's location.
他说的都是谎话，霍队长
Whatever he says, it's a lie, Hoggbottom.
霍队长，你听我说
Hoggbottom, listen to me!
天啊
Oh, God.
胡尼克
Nicholas Wilde!
怎么这么巧？
What are the chances?
这是我第一次坐牢，不得不说
You know, this is my first time in prison, and I gotta say,
这里的伙食真可口
their food is on point.
你怎么会在这？
How are you even here?
命运啊
Destiny.
加上被捕啦
Plus an arrest.
不过看样子茱蒂逃走了
But it looks like Judith got away.
那是你们共同的决定吗？
Was that decision mutual?
看来最佳搭档闹不合，想聊聊吗？
Sensing trouble in paradise. Wanna talk about it?
我只想离开这里
What I want is to get out of here.
对哦，你的伟大计划
Right, your big plan.
低调地在南方岛屿啜饮树袋熊调酒
Lay low on Outback Island sipping piña koalas.
但别相信树袋熊，他们有四根拇指
Except you can't trust koalas, 'cause they got four thumbs.
我有一整集播客在聊这件事
Did a whole episode about it on my podcast.
叫「四指树袋熊」
It was called "They Got Four Thumbs."
不过呢，至少他们不是鸭嘴兽
But you know what? At least they ain't platypuses.
你…拜托让我集中精神好吗？
Wait. Can you just...Can you please just let me concentrate?
收到
Roger that.
跟我聊聊嘛，兄弟
- Just talk to me, dude!
她最后跟你说什么？
What's the last thing she said to you?
她…
She, um...
她说也许我们太不一样了
Uh, she said maybe we are too different.
在那之前你说了什么？
And what did you say before that?
我说不值得为这个案子送命
I said the case isn't worth dying for.
就是…
Like, uh...
她不值得为它送命，因为…
like, you know, as in it isn't worth her dying for because...
我这种独来独往的动物没有真正的朋友
because solitary animals like me don't have real friends.
我…我不想失去她
And I... I... I don't want to lose her.
所以我就…
So, I just...
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know how to say that.
知道吗，兄弟？我想你都说了
You know what, bud? I think you just did.
等等，你怎么做的？
Wait, how'd you do that?
我张开手臂，环抱你
Well, I opened my arms,
然后用力挤
put them around you and then I squeezed.
这叫拥抱，狐狸不拥抱吗？
It's called a hug. Do foxes not have hugs?
开锁哦，对，那是河狸基本功
The lock. Yeah, that's Beave 101.
那只兔子在丘丘沙漠，出发
The rabbit's in Desert Dunes. Roll out!
快，出发
Hit it. Roll out!
你的搭档需要你
Your partner needs you,
聂狸宝带你去找她
and Nibbles Maplestick is gonna get you to her.
嘿，是那个狐狸，爸
Hey! It's the fox dad!
还有土拨鼠
And the woodchuck!
土拨鼠？我是河狸，再这样叫我…
Woodchuck? I'm a beaver! Call me that again--
-糟糕 -好，该走了，赶快走
- Oops. -Okay, go! We gotta go! Here we go!
给我回来
Get back here!
你好，尼克
Hello, Nicholas.
希望你喜欢我的新家
I hope you like my new home.
我用自己的毛编织的
I wove it with my own wool.
吓死你
- Jump scare!
后会有期
Adios!
（开）
我们自由了
-We're free!
-车子，我们需要车子，不…
- Wheels. We need wheels. -No, no.
不…
No, no, no, no.
对不起
I am sorry.
我们可能无法及时赶去帮茱蒂
I do not think we can get to Judy in time to help.
除非…
Unless...
你认识动物方城市史上最快的飙车手
...you happen to know the fastest driver in the history of Zootopia.
（飙速动物）
快侠，快如风的快侠
Hey, Flash, Flash Hundred Yard Dash.
搭档有难，得穿越市区，违规狂飙
Partner's in trouble. Need to get across town, ignore the laws.
不…
No...
早说
problem.
我们走
Let's hit it.
嘿
Hey.
还好有你 -老实跟你说
- Glad you're here. - I gotta tell ya,
我不相信树懒开车多可靠…
I'm not convinced a sloth is our most reliable--
哦耶
Oh, yeah! Whoo-hoo!
要点亮钟楼
To turn on the clock tower,
前往你外曾祖母的家，找到证书
and light the way to your great-grandma's home so we can find her patent,
我们得到电源控制室，通过这里
we need to reach the power control room through here.
-动作要快 否则… -我们会成功的，哈茱蒂
-But we have to move quickly or we're never-- -We shall succeed, Judy Hopps.
盖瑞，准备不够充分就功亏一篑，我不…
Look, Gary, if we don't over-prepare, we're underprepared and I don't...
我的家族努力了一百年
My family's been trying to prove
想证明我们不是大家想的那样
we're not what everyone thinks for a hundred years.
即使就差一点点
But even this close, they'd never want me
他们也不会把所有重担放在我肩膀上
to put the weight of the world on my shoulders.
因为我根本没肩膀
Because I don't have any shoulders.
我们会成功的
We shall succeed.
找到你了，兔子
I got you, rabbit.
我不知道茱蒂在哪就帮不了她
I cannot help Judy if I don't know where she is,
你得登入保罗的电脑，追踪霍队长
which is why I need you to get on Paul's computer and track Hoggbottom.
你可是逃犯欸
You are an escaped fugitive.
我跟你讲话都可能被炒鱿鱼
I could get fired for even talking to you.
他们要让她一睡不醒，快去
They're gonna put her to sleep! Do it!
好啦
Okay!
你试过重开机吗？
Did you try restarting it?
有试过不耍白痴吗？
Have you tried not being an idiot?
保罗，帮你买了甜甜圈
Hey, Paul. I got you some donuts.
糟糕 -谢了，洪金豹
- Oh, no! - Thanks, Clawhauser.
洪金豹！位置！
Clawhauser! Location!
（输入你的密码）
（密码）
不会吧
Oh, no.
我想我们得穿过这场庆典
I think we're gonna have to go through the festival.
庆典？
Festival?
他们优先追踪的是手机
The phone's the first thing they track.
走，快走
Go! Go!
洪金豹 -在查了
- Clawhauser! - I am working on it.
-有了 -太好了
- I got it! No! - Great, great, great.
不会吧
Now--
这是什么庆典？
Oh. What festival is this?
（热辣动物祭）
耶！
Yeah!
快点…
Move, move, move!
快点 -动作快
- Come on! - Go, go, go!
我们挺你，哈茱蒂
We are with you, Judy Hopps.
又见面了，斑马
We meet again, Zebra.
尖角来了
- Here come the horns! - Ow!
她往那道门跑…
She's going for the door. She's going for the door!
洪金豹，快没时间了
Clawhauser, we're out of time.
（你不是机器人）
有了
I got it!
（气候墙出入门）
沙漠极地区气候墙出入门
Desert Tundratown weather wall access door.
沙漠极地区气候墙出入门，快点
Desert Tundratown weather wall access door. Hurry!
那道墙里面有什么？ -电源控制室
- What is in that wall? - Power control room.
不过只控制极地区的旧区
But for, like, some old part of Tundratown.
我知道他们想干嘛，他们会毁了我们
I know what they're doing. They'll ruin us.
别再用镇静剂了，干掉他们
No more tranquilizers. Put them down.
厉先生 -干掉他们，快
- Sir. - Put them down. Now!
快开枪
Take the shot.
快开枪，动手
Take the shot! Do it!
茱蒂
Judy!
有蛇 -电源控制室？
- Snake! - Power control room?
要爬五层楼，走，快点
Uh, five flights up. Come on, hurry!
很多阶梯耶
That is a lot of stairs.
真有你的，兄弟，我爱你，欠你一次
Way to hustle, bud, I love ya! I owe ya!
要打开了，要打开了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's turning on. It's turning on!
狸宝？
No. Nibbles?
狸宝
Nibbles!
蛇！
Snake!
好冷
Cold!
卡住了
It's jammed.
别担心我，去找开关
Don't worry about me. Find the switch.
不…不是这些
No, no, no, no. Not these.
应该会…旧一点
It would be, uh... older.
有看到吗？
Can you see it?
钟楼的灯打开了吗？
Did we turn on the clock tower?
那里
There!
在那里
It's there!
成功了？我们能找到原始专利证书？
We did it? We can find the original patent?
尼克？
Nick?
门…锁住了…
The door... It's locked... We have to...
怎么会锁住？
How did it lock?
狸宝？开门
Nibbles?  Open it.
狸宝
Nibbles!
这臭门卡住了
Dang door stuck on me.
抱歉
Sorry.
上一个案件有点曲折
Last case there was kind of a twist.
我知道
I know.
我的天啊，我真的…
Oh, my gosh. I really...
我心跳得好厉害
Oh, my heart is pounding.
我以为你知道，我以为你知道
I thought you knew. I thought you knew.
抱歉，搭档
Sorry, partner.
不想把你丢在冰雪中，但是没办法
Hate to leave you out in the cold...but I'm gonna.
请别生我的气
Please don't be mad at me.
可是，你懂的
But, I mean, you get it.
我们一直很有默契，我跟你
We've always been on the same page. Me and you!
没人看好，对吧？
Underdogs, right?
你得证明你跟别人一样好
You gotta prove you're as good as everyone else.
你够资格
That you belong.
我知道，很惨
I know, it's messed up...
不过这是我的机会
...but this is my chance.
我得把握
I have to take it.
等我到了他外曾祖母家
'Cause when I get to his great-grandma's home,
烧了原始专利证书
and I burn the original patent,
就终于能在我家抬起头来
I'll finally be something in my family.
才能算是厉家人
And I'll finally belong too.
茱蒂？
Judy?
来乱的
Ruh-roh.
萝卜头？
Carrots?
得杜绝后患
No loose ends.
掰，搭档
Bye, partner.7
掰，哈茱蒂
Bye, Judy Hopps.
宝柏，拜托
Pawbert. Please.
你可以跟你的家人不一样
You can be different than your family.
我不想不一样
I don't want to be different.
尼克…
Nick...
茱蒂
Judy?
狸宝，看到她了吗？
Nibbles, do you see her?
没有，还没看到
No, nothing yet.
茱蒂
Judy.
尼克
Nick.
尼…
Ni...
我们会成功的
We shall succeed,
哈茱蒂
Judy Hopps.
别紧张，茱蒂派我来的
It's okay. Judy sent me.
她得找到尼克
She needs to find Nick.
对，早该料到了
Yep. Should've seen that coming.
茱蒂
Judy!
尼克
Nick.
我们…会…成功
We... shall... succeed.
茱蒂
Judy...
我动不了
I can't move.
你又太冷，帮不上忙
And you're too cold to help.
而他就要…
And he's gonna...
尼克就要…
Nick's gonna...
茱蒂
Judy...
这个世界的责任从来就不该
The world was never meant to be
落在一只动物的肩上
on one animal's shoulders.
所以我外曾祖母才希望
That's why my great-grandma wanted
大家都能住在动物方城市
Zootopia to be for everyone.
这样我们才能互相帮忙
So, we could all help each other.
我没帮上忙
I didn't help.
你有
You did.
你选择帮助我
You chose to help me
成为我最好的温血动物朋友
and became my best warm-blooded friend.
非常温暖
Very warm.
我可以抱你吗？
Permission to hug?
我们要救你，还要救你的朋友
We're gonna save you and save your friend.
茱蒂
- Judy!
嘿，他要吃了那只兔子
Hey, he's gonna eat that rabbit!
不，等等，我想救她
No, wait! I'm saving her!
我去拿血清笔
I'm gonna get her the anti-pen.
她在哪？
Where is she?
她没熬过来
She... She didn't make it.
不过被蛇咬会走得很快
But with snake bites, you go fast.
等着瞧
You'll see.
不
No.
她走了，尼克，不要挣扎了
She's gone, Nick. Just get it over with!
你完了
- You're done.
赶快放弃吧
- Know when to quit!
抗毒血清
Anti-venom!
你能用抗毒血清救她，包包丢给我
You can save her with the anti-venom! Throw me the bag!
茱蒂
Judy!
算了，你会害死我们
Leave it! You're gonna kill us both.
不值得为它送命
It's not worth dying for.
我可不这么认为
Agree to disagree.
将我刺入心脏
Stab me straight into the heart.
我想去找你 -我以为…他说你…
- I thought... He told me you... - I was trying to get to you.
我看到你… -你已经…
- And I saw you... - ...that you were...
我去帮你们的朋友
I'll help your friend.
好，我不在乎我们不一样
Okay.  I don't care that we're different.
懂吗？我…
You know? I...
我在乎的…是你
What I care about is you.
我在乎你
I care about you.
懂吗？
Okay?
我没说出来
And I didn't say it.
我应该说的
I should've said it.
但是没说
But I didn't
因为…
because...
唉呀
uh, well...
因为我缺乏安全感
...'cause I am an emotionally insecure
又造成你不舒服
source of your discomfort,
不擅长表达自己的感受
who's not good at expressing his feelings.
可能是我始终独来独往
Probably because I've been on my own my whole life.
那不是借口，只是…
It's not an excuse. It's just...
所以我才没告诉你
It's why instead of telling you
你是我一生中最好的礼物
that you're the best thing that ever happened to me,
反而拿你的耳朵开玩笑
I-I make jokes about your ears.
我还跟你说你太拼命
And-And I tell you that you try too hard,
其实
when, you know, the truth is
我只是不要你受伤
I just don't want you to get hurt.
因为…
Because...
对我来说在这世上
Because no one else in the world
没有谁比你更重要
matters more to me than you do.
我是太拼了，因为内心里
I... I do try too hard because deep down
我怕自己就是大家以为的那样
I'm afraid that I am what everyone thinks I am.
我压抑不安，担心它让我显得软弱
And I suppress my discomfort because I'm worried it makes me look weak,
我想要坚强，但总是做不好
and I wanna be strong, and I think I'm failing all the time.
我把你的话当真，因为在我的生活中
And I only take what you say personally because you're the only one in my life
只有你相信我，就连我都不相信自己
who ever believed in me, even when I don't even believe in myself.
我早该跟你说的
And I should have told you that.
对我来说，世上没有谁比你更重要
No one else in the world matters to me more than you do either.
我有童年创伤，但我拒绝谈它
I have unresolved childhood trauma that I refuse to discuss
因为我怕展现脆弱的一面
because being vulnerable scares me.
不健康的英雄情结害我做出危险决定
I make dangerous choices because I have an unhealthy bunny hero complex.
我加入ZPD不是想当警察
And I didn't join the ZPD because I wanted to be a cop.
而是我一直想要有归属感
I joined because I always wanted to be part of a pack.
一想到会失去你就让我害怕，因为…
And the thought of losing you scares me because...
因为你是我的伙伴
because you're my pack.
我不该丢下你的
I should never have left you,
我确实需要看一群咨询师
and I do need a herd of therapy animals.
我该告诉你，你是我唯一想要的搭档
And I should have told you that you are the only partner
因为你是我的兔窝窝
I would ever want because...you're my fluffle.
就是一窝兔子啦
That's a bunch of rabbits.
这就叫内心话大爆发
Now that is what we call an overshare.
我还活着哦，熬过来了
I'm alive by the way. I made it.
那家伙也还活着
Oh! Also that guy is still alive.
嘿…小偷
- Hey! Hey! Thief!
他要到废弃的爬虫类社区
He's gonna get to the lost reptile neighborhood,
找到盖瑞外曾祖母的专利证书再销毁它
find Gary's great-grandma's patent and destroy it.
我不懂什么意思或盖瑞是谁，不过出发
Yeah, I've got no idea what that means, or who Gary is, but let's go!
哈胡双雄？ -胡哈双雄
- Hopps and Wilde? - Wilde and Hopps.
还有狸宝与盖瑞
And Nibbles and Gary!
他是盖瑞
He's Gary.
谢啦，给蛇用的，他会冷，身上没毛
Thank you. It's for the snake. He's cold. No fur on him.
你这个小… -掰咯
- Why, you little... - Bye now.
-你！你不配进这个家 -爸，等等…
-You! You don't belong in this family! -Dad! Wait, wait, wait!
-爸 -你永远都不是这个家的一分子
-Dad! You will never belong in this family!
等等…我没跟他们一伙，我在帮我们
Wait, wait! I wasn't working with them. I was helping us.
我知道爬虫类社区埋在哪里
I know where the reptile neighborhood is buried.
证明蛇发明气候墙的专利证书在哪
Where to find the real patent that proves that snakes invented the walls.
我打算销毁它，为了厉家
I'm going to destroy it, for the family.
为了你，爸爸
For you, Daddy.
你想保住工作，就给我闭嘴
You want to keep your job, you say nothing.
你
You!
也许你是厉家人
Maybe you are a Lynxley.
带我去找专利证书
Take me to the patent.
三个就能成虎
It takes a threesome to be somethin',
但有四个才能破门而入
but a four-way to bust your doorway.
去拿专利证书，销毁它
Get to the patent! Destroy it!
快去，交给我们
Go! We got this.
臭猫咪，别想再伤害我的城市
Hey, whiskers, you're done hurtin' muh city.
惨了，气势改变了
Uh-oh. Tides have turned.
嘿，马立夯
Hey, Brian Winddancer!
你想当英雄，还是你只会演戏？
You want to be a hero, or just play one on TV? Ow!
好，我往左，你往右？
Okay, I go left, and you go right?
好
Uh, yeah.
或者…
Or...
你开车的技术好烂
You are a horrible driver.
没错
Yes, I am.
我要跳了
I'm gonna jump!
携手同行
Zoogetherness. Huh?
算了，当我没说，跳吧
No, never mind. Forget I said it. Here we go.
火柴…
Matches, matches, matches, matches.
我们兔子会挖洞
Bunnies, we're burrowers.
兔兔无影脚
Rabbit kick. Hi-yah!
我会销毁专利证书
I'll destroy the patent,
那个社区和里面的一切
that town and everything in it.
一只脏狐狸和一只傻兔子
And a dirtbag fox and a dumb bunny
休想坏了我的好事
will never stand in my way.
她不是傻兔子，而且你忘了一件事
She's not a dumb bunny, and you're forgetting one thing.
什么事？
What's that?
我们的朋友是蛇
We're friends with a snake.
你好，搭档
- Howdy, partner.
接住
- Heads up!
爸爸 -你爸在忙
- Daddy! - Daddy's busy.
马立夯！过去！
Brian! Go!
你说「正义已死」
You say justice is dead...
我说「不可能」
...I say neigh!
来啊，猫咪猫咪 -不
- Here, kitty-kitty. - No!
这叫逮捕，亲爱的
It's called an arrest, sweetheart.
砰
Boom.
没人会相信你们而不信我们
No one will believe you over us.
我们永远比你们高尚
We've always been better than you.
永远都是
And we always will be.
你们做什么都不重要
Nothing you do matters.
可是，对他很重要
Well, it matters to him.
走吧？
Shall we?
一只长袜
One long sock.
（佘宅）
（原始专利证书）
我要把它们全部烧成灰
I'm gonna burn it all to the ground!
我是真正的厉家人
I'm a real Lynxley!
可以了，猪仔，可以了
That'll do, pig. That'll do.
今天有惊人的新闻
Astonishing news today
哈茱蒂与胡尼克警员
after officers Judy Hopps and Nicholas Wilde
在一条蝮蛇和一只河狸协助下
along with a pit viper and a beaver
阻止了另一桩重大阴谋
foiled another major conspiracy
揭露本市气候墙的真正发明人
by revealing the true inventor of the city's weather walls
是一条蛇
was a snake.
还发现是颜面尽失的厉家
While the now disgraced Lynxley family
窃取了原本的蓝图
were revealed to have stolen the original plans
并掩盖事实数十年
and covered it up for decades.
你们还会再见到厉弥…
You have not heard the last of Milton Lyn...
他们的极地区扩建计划已正式取消
Their Tundratown expansion now officially canceled.
有人说你们是梦幻搭档，怎么做到的？
Some are calling you the dream team. How did you do it?
世界上有很多不同的动物
Uh... Well, there's a lot of different animals out there.
有时候
And sometimes, we start to look
我们开始注意到彼此不同的原因
at all the little reasons that we're not the same.
这让我们担忧
And it makes us worry.
但如果我们多跟彼此沟通
But maybe if we just talked to each other,
试着了解彼此的想法
if we just tried to understand one another,
我们会发现那些差异根本…
we would see that our differences don't really make
（抱歉我咬了你，盖瑞）
没影响
any difference at all.
甚至会发现你我各自的特点
Maybe we'd even see that what makes me me and you you,
能让我们更坚强
can make us even stronger.
只要努力，第二年就会做到这点
And with hard work, you're gonna get to that by year two!
对\Yeah
-斑宝 -其实我叫金恩
-Zebros. -Actually, my name is Gene.
我的名字也叫金恩
My name...is also Gene.
-斑宝 -斑宝
- Zebros! - Zebros!
（欢迎回来！）
都是他
He did it!
孩子们，别缠着蛇
Kids, get off the snake.
嗨，大家好吗？
- Hi. How is everybody doing?
等一下
Oh! One sec!
他们是我的家人
This is my family.
可以抱你吗？
Permission to hug?
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿，我有东西送你
Hey, uh, I got you something.
爱你哦，搭档
Love you, partner.
但我还是我，所以十年才说一次
But I am still me, so I'm only saying it once a decade.
爱你哦，搭档
Love you, partner.
你得还我
Oh, I'm gonna need that back.
侦破下个案子之后再还给你
I'll give it back to you after our next case.
会有下一个案子？
There's gonna be another case, huh?
当然，因为你越狱时
Of course. Because, when you broke out of jail,
也释放了两百名高危险囚犯
you also released 200 highly dangerous prisoners.
值得
Worth it.
那你想从哪里开始呢？
Any idea where you want to start?
（南方岛屿，树袋熊调酒之乡）
Oh. Mmm. Mmm.
到南方岛屿的单程票一张，头等舱
One-way ticket to Outback Island, please. First class.
非常好
Very nice.
别忘了，如果满意我们的服务
Oh, and remember, if you're happy with our service,
记得给我们四根大拇指
please be sure to leave us four thumbs up.
我会的
Oh, I will.
哈胡双雄？
Hopps and Wilde?
胡尼克和蔡楚蒂
Wilde and Cabbagepatch.
动物方城市2
动物方城市，来吧
Zootopia, vamos!
热辣动物祭，动起来
Burning Mammal, let's go!
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
生活在疯狂世界
♪ We live in a crazy world ♪
竞争又仓促
♪ Caught up in a rat race ♪
水泥丛林生活
♪ Concrete jungle life ♪
有时失常
♪ Is sometimes a mad place ♪
狂野的一日结束
♪ It's you and me together ♪
你和我在一起
♪ At the end of a wild day ♪
不要压抑不语
♪ Don't keep it All bottled up ♪
释放你的精力
♪ And release your energy ♪
为了庆祝，我们齐聚一堂
♪ Only reason we are here Is to celebrate ♪
在这里人人都能出人头地
♪ In a place where anyone Can be anything ♪
珍惜这一刻，别让它流逝
♪ Hold on to this moment Don't let it fade away ♪
宝贝，音乐继续播送
♪ Baby Keep the music playin' ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
来吧，保持下去
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun If you're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
动物园
♪ A zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
生在热力时代
♪ We live in a heated time ♪
没机会冷却
♪ No chance to cool down ♪
不断受限
♪ Continuously confined ♪
现在怎么办？
♪ What do we do now? ♪
重要的是寻找爱
♪ It's all about Finding love ♪
有时难以遇见
♪ Sometimes hard to come by ♪
但当它迎面而来，总是很愉快
♪ But when it comes to us It's always a good time♪
为了庆祝，我们齐聚一堂
♪ Only reason we are here Is to celebrate ♪
在这里人人都能出人头地
♪ In a place where anyone Can be anything ♪
珍惜这一刻，别让它流逝
♪ Hold on to this moment Don't let it fade away ♪
（欢迎光临沼泽市场）
宝贝，音乐继续播送
♪ Baby Keep the music playin' ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
来吧，保持下去
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun If you're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
动物园
♪ A zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
我带你高飞
♪ I'll take you higher ♪
我们无法驯服
♪ We can't be tamed ♪
宝贝，我带你高飞
♪ Baby, I'll take you higher ♪
我带你高飞
♪ I'll take you higher ♪
我们无法驯服
♪ And we can't be tamed ♪
宝贝，我带你高飞
♪ Baby, I'll take you higher ♪
♪ Es una fiesta Que sube como la espuma ♪
♪Yo por ti iré hasta La luna de ida y vuelta ♪
♪ Es una fiesta que sube Como la espuma ♪
♪ Yo por ti iré hasta La luna de ida y vuelta ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
（第一次搭档就上手）
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
快点，保持下去
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun If you're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
快点，站起来
♪ Come on, get on up ♪
我们狂野，无法驯服
♪ We're wild And we can't be tamed ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
来吧，保持下去
♪ Come on, keep it up ♪
只要你肯进场玩
♪ It's fun If you're down to play ♪
我们要把舞池变成动物园
♪ And we're turnin' the floor Into a zoo-ooh-ooh ♪
主题曲 "Zoo"
表演者 夏奇拉
作曲及作词  艾德·希兰
制作人  布莱克·斯莱特金 、亚历克斯·(A.C.)·卡斯蒂略、夏奇拉 与 艾德·希兰
主题曲 "Zoo"
表演者 夏奇拉
作曲及作词  艾德·希兰
制作人  布莱克·斯莱特金 、亚历克斯·(A.C.)·卡斯蒂略、夏奇拉 与 艾德·希兰
（给萝卜头）
（你的精神支持动物赠）
爱你哦，搭档
Love you, partner.
兔子，你要播整晚吗？
Hey, bunny. Ya gonna keep playing that all night?
别烦她，她觉得很自豪
Leave her alone. She's proud of herself,
但还是要外界的肯定
but still seeks external validation.
闭嘴 -你闭嘴
- Oh, shut up! - You shut up!
你才闭嘴
You shut up!
兔子，你们俩下个案子是什么？
Hey, bunny, what's next for you two?
我们要调查一只勒死邻居的兔子
Uh, we're investigating a rabbit who strangled her neighbors.
你惹毛她了啦
You offended her.
是你惹毛她 -闭嘴
- You offended her! - Shut up.
晚安 -你闭嘴
- Good night! - You shut up.